BRANISLAV VUCETIC

Mechanical Engineer

Contact

Novi Sad +381 63 546 933

vucetic985@gmail.com
in VuceticBranislav

VuceticBranislav-Portfolio

Languages

English – B1 Norwegian – A1

Interests

Programming Board Games Video Games

Personal Skills

Problem solving Curiosity Desire to learn Highly motivated

Summary

A senior mechanical engineer with over 12 years of experience, specializing in various analysis and calculations of pressure equipment and aboveground storage tanks. Familiar with relevant design codes. Basic knowledge of FEA and structural analysis. Strong problem-solving abilities and constructive thinking developed through years of experience. I have a year and a half of experience as a junior software developer in .NET and Azure.

Education

♦ Jan 2021 - October 2021:

BRAINS Online 2020, National IT requalification program 5-module course thought by VOICT leading to Java Junior Web Developer level competences. Completed with teacher's commendation

♦ Sep 2006 – Jul 2010:

Master of Science degree in Mechanical Engineering, Production Engineering study programme, Faculty of Technical Sciences, University of Novi Sad.

♦ Sep 2003 – Sep 2006:

Mechanical Engineer, Technical College "Viša Tehnička Škola", Zrenjanin.

Projects

♦ Drafting:

Preparing and reviewing mechanical drawings. Ensuring drawing accuracy and compliance with code and requisitions.

♦ Calculation and Analiysis:

Various calculations according to pressure codes such as ASME BPVC, EN13445, PD5500, GOST, and RToD. Involved in FEA calculations as well as inhouse calculations. Validating calculation results to ensure code compliance and accuracy.

♦ Modeling:

Preparing 3D models in Inventor for FEA calculations. Modeling using Dlubal RFEM and FE Pipe.

Working Experience

May 2011 – Jan 2022:

♦ Mechanical Engineer - Hitard Engineering, Office Novi Sad.

Preparing and reviewing mechanical drawings and calculations of pressure vessels.

Jan 2022 - Jun 2023:

♦ Junior Software Developer – Levi9, Office Novi Sad.

Backend developement using .NET and Microsoft Azure. Modernize old COBOL mainframe code to .NET.

Jun 2023 – Present:

♦ Senior Mechanical Engineer — Hitard Engineering, Office Novi Sad.

Preparing and reviewing mechanical design drawings and calculations. Perform various calculations in accordance with design codes, client specifications and good engineering practices. Author of various in-house calculations based on general mechanics.

Skills

- AutoCAD, Inventor, Sold Works
- ♦ Midas NX
- ♦ Nozzle PRO, FE Pipe
- ♦ Dlubal RFEM
- ♦ MathCAD

- Autopipe Vessel
- ♦ PVElite
- ♦ VVS
- ♦ Compress
- ♦ AMETank